nwf.org 2019-09-21

# Privacy Policy | National Wildlife Federation

## National Wildlife Federation — Online Privacy Policy

We value the support of our members, donors, customers, and others who support the National Wildlife Federation (NWF), a Family of Organizations comprising NWF, [National Wildlife Action Fund](http://www.nwf.org/action), and NWF Affiliates, through visiting our websites. We know protecting personal information is important, and we respect your privacy.

Our privacy policy is available in the footer of every page of our website. If you have questions or concerns regarding our site's privacy statement, your personal information, or how it will be used, or would like to review or correct your personal information, contact NWF directly at www.nwf.org/Contact-Us. If you disagree with any of the terms herein, please immediately discontinue use of our websites, mobile sites and applications.

####  Types of Information We May Collect and How We May Collect It

**General Browsing Information** — If you visit any of our web properties, mobile sites or applications for general browsing or if you download any collateral assets from a web property, we may generate a “cookie” to collect and store the following general information in order to analyze trends, gather broad demographic information, and monitor site traffic patterns that can help us further develop and improve design and functionality: your computer's IP address, web browser type, mobile device type, and operating system, the date and time you access our site, the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site and/or the exit page in which you linked away from our site or application; this is also subject to identify various pages that you visited while generally browsing on our site or application. NWF uses a cookie on our website properties, mobile sites and applications for consent to browsing data collection. For more information please reference the “Cookies, Consent and Tracking” section of our policy.

**Personally Identifiable Information** — If you visit any of our web properties, mobile sites or applications and take any of the following actions: provide your name, email address, physical address, credit card information, participate in social media sharing—information that identifies you as an individual or relates to an identifiable person, we will explicitly notify you before we collect this data and will not collect it unless you choose to provide it to us. If you participate and opt in to our Single Sign-On (SSO) provider, we may collect limited information necessary to identify you against our authentication services. Please reference the Single Sign-On (SSO) section for more information.

The types of personal data may vary depending on the type of activity you are engaged in. The personal data NWF may collect, process and use may include, but are not limited to your name, email address, phone number, photo or other image, birth date, sex, address, friend connections, credit card information, shipping information; and location (only if directly identifiable to you, otherwise NWF treats location as non-personal data).

If you choose to share the name of and contact information for someone who might be interested in engaging with NWF, NWF may store that individual’s name and contact details that you provided to NWF.

NWF may use tools or third-party analytical software to automatically collect and use certain non-personal data that does not directly enable NWF to identify you. For purposes of this Privacy Policy, “non-personal data” means information that does not directly identify you. The types of non-personal data NWF may collect and use include, but are not limited to: (i) device properties, including, but not limited to unique device identifier or other device identifier ("UDID"); (ii) device software platform and firmware; (iii) mobile phone carrier; (iv) geographical data such as zip code, area code and location; (v) game score and achievements; (vi) third party anonymized or pseudonymized ID; (vi) other non-personal data as reasonably required by NWF to enhance the services and other NWF products and services.

####  Single Sign-On (SSO) 

Single Sign-On is an identity provider service that creates and manages user identity information for the purpose of providing authentication services so that we can offer a single user account for multiple NWF services and methods of engagement. Authentication processes utilize data that you are or have previously provided. If your Single Sign-On (SSO) account is removed or deleted, you will no longer have access to a single user account.

####  European Union and California Privacy Rights

NWF is committed to ensuring the security and protection of the information we possess and to provide an approach to data protection that adheres to relevant data protection laws and regulations.

While these terms explain how we collect and use your information, if you are an individual in a European Union nation or a California resident, you may request information about our use of your personal information. To make such a request, please send an email to: [dataprotection@nwf.org](mailto:dataprotection@nwf.org). 

**Children's Information** — NWF provides a special place on our website for children and we encourage parents and guardians to visit this part of our site with their children. We respect the privacy of children, and do not collect any more personal information than reasonably necessary to enable them to participate in the activities we offer at our Website. We do not have any agreements with outside organizations to collect personal information at our site. The information we collect from children is used to respond to children's specific requests to participate in activities such as:

  * contests or sweepstakes
  * subscription to an online newsletter
  * voting in polls or otherwise expressing an opinion
  * sending electronic greeting cards
  * to tailor/customize the visitor's experience at our site

If you are under 13 years of age or a minor in your country of residence, please ask your legal guardian’s permission to use or access the services. NWF takes children’s privacy seriously, and encourages parents and/or guardians to play an active role in their children's online experience at all times. NWF does not knowingly collect any personal information from children below the aforementioned age and if NWF learns that NWF has inadvertently gathered personal data from children under the aforementioned age, NWF will take reasonable measures to promptly erase such personal data from NWF’s records.

We do not share children's personal information with anyone other than those who provide support for the internal operations of the Website and our agents (e.g., contractors who provide fulfillment services or technical support to the Website). Parents can review the information that we have collected from their children online, prevent the further use or maintenance of such information, or direct the deletion of their children's personal information by emailing us at this address: [rangerrick@nwf.org](mailto:rangerrick@nwf.org).

####  How We May Use Collected Information

**Use of General and Personally Identifiable Information  **— ** ** Information may be shared within NWF's Family of Organizations for the purposes of fulfilling your orders and requests, responding to any comments or questions you submit, and/or providing follow-up information about the NWF Family of Organizations, or analysis to help us better understand our member and supporter base. We may outsource to third parties one or more of these functions. Please note, NWF will only share personally identifiable information with the NWF Affiliate located in your state.

NWF may use and disclose to NWF’s Family of Organizations and NWF’s partners and contractors the collected non-personal data for purposes of analyzing usage of the services, advertisement serving, managing, and development of other NWF services and products.

From time to time, we may send information to you via email from other organizations that we believe may be of interest to you or can provide services that will be of use to you, or we may share your postal address with such organizations. We will not share your email address with other organizations. If you receive an email from us, you may choose not to receive such messages in the future by clicking the "unsubscribe" link which we put in the footer of each email. We provide a similar process in our postal mailings. If you prefer that we not exchange your name with other reputable organizations, or if you wish to modify future marketing offers from NWF via postal mail, please call 1-800-822-9919. If you have further questions or concerns, please contact us.

**Cookies, Consent and Tracking** — NWF creates “cookies” when your browser accesses our website applications, services and systems. Cookies are pieces of data created by websites you visit and are stored on your local computer or mobile device. Cookies can expire after a period of time specified in the cookie, this ranges from days to as long as a year.

Some areas of our site and systems require the use of “cookies” to enhance user experience and are essential to the functionality and analytics tracking of the site or system. If a user rejects a “cookie” or explicit “cookie policy,” they simply will not be able to use that part of the site or system effectively and may be asked to accept the “cookie” or “cookie policy” at a later time.

NWF treats information collected by “cookies” to keep user sessions, remember site preferences, provide single sign-on abilities, personalize relevant content and enhance user experience. NWF may combine this information with other information NWF has about you, and NWF may use that information to improve the services and/or provide customized communications to you.

**Advertisements** — NWF reserves the right to use and disclose the collected data for purposes of advertisement by NWF’s Family of Organizations or NWF’s partners and contractors. NWF may use third-party advertising companies to serve advertisements that may be of interest to you when you access and use our web properties, mobile sites and applications based on information relating to your access to and use of the website(s). To do so, these companies may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser (including through use of pixel tags). If you would like [more information about this practice](https://www.aboutads.info/) and to learn about your choices in connection with it, please visit [https://optout.networkadvertising.org](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

You recognize and agree that the advertising companies who deliver ads for NWF may combine the information collected with other information they have independently collected from other services or products. These companies collect and use information under their own privacy policies. These ad-serving technologies are integrated into services; if you do not want to be subject to this technology, do not use or access services. Although NWF takes commercially reasonable steps to instruct such advertising companies to comply with the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, NWF does not have access to or control of third party technologies.

####  Further Use of Collected Information

**Publicly Sharing Your Comments and Stories** — NWF often receives offline information from our website visitors and supporters who have successfully participated in our programs and/or employed our resources. In certain instances, we would like to publicly share the comments and stories we receive by posting this information on our website or other platforms. We will not, however, publicly share any information we receive on our website without first receiving the express consent of the individual who submitted the information. Furthermore, we will not post information in any way that specifically identifies the sender of that information unless the sender approves it.

**Partners** — NWF may store and/or transfer your personal data to its partners in and outside of EU/EEA member states and the United States in accordance with mandatory legislation and this Privacy Policy. NWF may disclose your personal data to third parties in connection with a merger, consolidation, restructuring, the sale of substantially all of NWF’s stock and/or assets or other corporate change, including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process provided, however, that this Privacy Policy shall continue to govern such personal data.

####  Third Party Terms and Conditions

Please note that your access to and use of the services may be subject to certain third party terms and conditions and privacy policies, including but not limited to application stores, mobile software platforms, online gaming platforms, social networking services and payment providers. You recognize and agree that NWF is not liable for any such third party terms and conditions and their use of your personal data.

NWF may in its discretion make available links through advertisements or otherwise enable you to access third-party products or services. Please note that, while using such products or services, you are using products or services developed and administered by people or companies not affiliated with or controlled by NWF. NWF is not responsible for the actions of those people or companies, the content of their products or services, the use of information you provide to them, or any products or services they may offer. The fact that NWF is linking to those products or services does not constitute our sponsorship of, or affiliation with, those people or companies.

Please note that certain services that NWF may offer, such as multiplayer gaming, social networking and gaming console services, may use third-party services to provide authentication for the services with a gaming console ID, social networking ID or gaming network account. When you register to join or use the services from a third-party gaming or social networking system, certain personally identifiable user and/or membership data may be transferred automatically to and from NWF and you hereby consent to the processing, using, combining, disclosing and retaining of such data in accordance with this Privacy Policy by NWF.

####  Security Measures

We provide our visitors with a secure experience. Our technical security measures include industry standard SSL 2048-bit encryption with SHA-256 to secure the transfer of data between your web browser and our servers. Our web traffic is managed by a load balancer using Transport Layer Security (TLS) 1.2 to establish secure commination channels to distribute network and application traffic across a number of servers. TLS protects the confidentiality and integrity of the information being passes between systems. We adhere to industry standards for safeguarding the privacy of your personal information when interacting with our systems.

When users interact with sensitive information (such as a credit card number or personal identifiable information), that data is encrypted and is protected with the best industry standard encryption algorithm. While on a secure page, the lock icon in your web browser's Internet address bar becomes locked, indicting your connection is secure.

Please be aware that there are ongoing changes to security to social networking and third-party public access services that NWF may make available to you. You may choose to disclose information about yourself by contributing user generated content to these services. Any data that you disclose in forums, blogs, chats or social platforms carries no expectation of privacy or confidentiality. NWF is not responsible for any personal data you choose to make public.

NWF reserves the right to amend this policy at any time as needed. We will post changes here, so please check back periodically. Changes will take effect when posted, and your continued use of the site will constitute your agreement to the changes. Thank you.
